<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python programming</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Python programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 13:10:47 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Turtle programming</title>
      <link>/basics/turtle_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 13:10:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/turtle_programming/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Learn key syntax in turtle Draw the first turtle graphic Draw shapes in practice  Syntax table    Keyword description     import import statement is the most common way of invocking the required modules   star mark(*) stands for everything   forward(distance) Parameter: distance- is a number (integer or float). Move the turtle forward by the specified distance, in the direction the turtle is headed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numbers, strings, list I</title>
      <link>/basics/numbers_strings_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 15:24:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/numbers_strings_list/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction in this class Brief introduction to Numbers Brief introduction to Strings Brief introduction to List How to do it in turtle? Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     width(integer) Defines the width of the pen. Patameter - integer is a value type of int   if statement is a conditional statement.   for statement is a loop statement in which operations repeat itself for a limited amount of time    Brief introduction to Number What is Number?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loops, If...else, Tuple</title>
      <link>/basics/loops_conditionals_tuple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 20:43:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/loops_conditionals_tuple/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction in this class What is Loop statement? What is if&amp;hellip;else statement? What is Tuple? Exercises with little turtle Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     width(integer) Defines the width of the pen. Patameter - integer is a value type of int   if statement is a conditional statement.   for statement is a loop statement in which operations repeat itself for a limited amount of time    What is loop statement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting, string and list slicing</title>
      <link>/basics/slicing_and_formatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 19:31:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/slicing_and_formatting/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction String slicing and formatting How to add items to a List? List slicing More on list Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     str.format() Perform a string formatting operation. The string on which this method is called can contain literal text or replacement fields delimited by braces {}. Each replacement field contains either the numeric index of a positional argument, or the name of a keyword argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>While and Function</title>
      <link>/basics/while_and_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 13:52:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/while_and_function/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction How does while loop work? How to define a function? Define a function with default argument values Call a function in another function Yin Yang example of function calls Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     def The keyword def introduces a function definition. It must be followed by the function name and the parenthesized list of formal parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objects I</title>
      <link>/basics/objects_and_game_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:25:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/objects_and_game_design/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction What is an object? Objects in game design Guessing game Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     class A class is a code template for creating objects. Objects have member variables and have behaviour associated with them. In python a class is created by the keyword class. An object is created using the constructor of the class.    What is an object?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>