<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python programming</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Python programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 13:49:38 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>String 1</title>
      <link>/exercises/string_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 13:49:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exercises/string_1/</guid>
      <description>Exercise 1 Write a program to calculate the length of a string.
For example:
string = &#39;Practice makes perfect&#39;  Length of this string is 20
 Not allowed to use len() (不允许使用len()函数)
  Exercise 2 Given a string consists of lower and upper case letters, write a program to convert lower case to upper case and upper case to lower case, return the result.
For example:
# Input string = &#39;I hAVe UPPeR caSE AnD lowER CasE LETteRs&#39; # Output result = &#39;i HavE uppEr CAse aNd LOWer cASe letTErS&#39;   Hint: lower() and uppwer() are Python functions to convert upper to lower and vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turtle programming</title>
      <link>/basics/turtle_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 13:10:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/turtle_programming/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Learn key syntax in turtle Draw the first turtle graphic Draw shapes in practice  Syntax table    Keyword description     import import statement is the most common way of invocking the required modules   star mark(*) stands for everything   forward(distance) Parameter: distance- is a number (integer or float). Move the turtle forward by the specified distance, in the direction the turtle is headed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String 2</title>
      <link>/exercises/string_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 13:54:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exercises/string_2/</guid>
      <description>String Exercises Given a string below:
str01 = &#39;This is a sample string&#39;  Exercise 1 Check if string am exists in string str01, print am is exist if it&amp;rsquo;s exist.
 【Hint】  Step 1: Do if...else check if string am exists in the string str01 Step 2: Print am is exist if it does.   Exercise 2 Write a program to convert the following list to string.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numbers, Strings, Operators</title>
      <link>/basics/numbers_strings_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 15:24:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/numbers_strings_list/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction in this class Number String List How to do it in turtle? Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     width(integer) Defines the width of the pen. Patameter - integer is a value type of int   if statement is a conditional statement.   for statement is a loop statement in which operations repeat itself for a limited amount of time    Number What is Number?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loops, If...else, List</title>
      <link>/basics/loops_conditionals_tuple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 20:43:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/loops_conditionals_tuple/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction in this class Brief introduction to List What is Loop statement? What is if&amp;hellip;else statement? Exercises with little turtle Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     width(integer) Defines the width of the pen. Patameter - integer is a value type of int   if statement is a conditional statement.   for statement is a loop statement in which operations repeat itself for a limited amount of time    List What is List?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting, string and list slicing</title>
      <link>/basics/slicing_and_formatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 19:31:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/slicing_and_formatting/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction String slicing and formatting How to add items to a List? List slicing More on list Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     str.format() Perform a string formatting operation. The string on which this method is called can contain literal text or replacement fields delimited by braces {}. Each replacement field contains either the numeric index of a positional argument, or the name of a keyword argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>While and Function</title>
      <link>/basics/while_and_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 13:52:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/while_and_function/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction How does while loop work? How to define a function? Define a function with default argument values Call a function in another function Yin Yang example of function calls Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     def The keyword def introduces a function definition. It must be followed by the function name and the parenthesized list of formal parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objects I</title>
      <link>/basics/objects_and_game_design_i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:25:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/objects_and_game_design_i/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction What is an object? Objects in game design Guessing game Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     class A class is a code template for creating objects. Objects have member variables and have behaviour associated with them. In python a class is created by the keyword class. An object is created using the constructor of the class.    What is an object?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object II and Dictionary</title>
      <link>/basics/objects_ii_and_dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 12:45:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/objects_ii_and_dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction Dictionary Looping techniques Students information system design Homework  Syntax table    Syntax Description     Dictionary It is best to think of a dictionary as a set of key: value pairs, with the requirement that the keys are unique (within one dictionary). A pair of braces creates an empty dictionary: {}. Placing a comma-separated list of key:value pairs within the braces adds initial key:value pairs to the dictionary; this is also the way dictionaries are written on output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules</title>
      <link>/basics/modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 14:07:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/modules/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction Module Standard Modules Looking for more fun? Homework  Syntax table    Syntax Description     Module A module is a file containing Python definitions and statements.   Standard Modules Python comes with a library of standard modules, described in a separate document, the Python Library Reference (“Library Reference” hereafter). Some modules are built into the interpreter; these provide access to operations that are not part of the core of the language but are nevertheless built in, either for efficiency or to provide access to operating system primitives such as system calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input &amp; Output</title>
      <link>/basics/io/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 18:44:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/basics/io/</guid>
      <description>Class objectives  Key syntax introduction Create a directory or directories Create a file Read and write file Classroom xercise Homework  Syntax table    Keyword description     mkdir A function to create a single directory, returns a directory object.   makedirs A function to create a multiple directories, returns a multiple nested directories.   open() open() returns a file object, and is most commonly used with two arguments: open(filename, mode).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/introduction/python%E8%AF%BE%E7%A8%8B%E7%AE%80%E4%BB%8B/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/python%E8%AF%BE%E7%A8%8B%E7%AE%80%E4%BB%8B/</guid>
      <description>Python课程简介 什么是Python？ Python是一门易读，易学，易维护的计算机程序设计语言。1991年由Guido van Rossum设计。2017年成为年度程序语言。是目前软件开发，科学计算，人工智能和教育领域最流行的一门面呈语言。
为什么学Python？  参加青少年信息学奥林匹克比赛(NOI)或者(USACO) 学习各类游戏开发。小到“贪吃蛇“和”俄罗斯方块“大到“超级马里奥”和各种RPG游戏。 学习网页开发，学会从零开始制作自己的博客 科学计算及大数据分析。通过Python可以分析大量数据并分类处理。 自动化日常生活及工作中重复性极高的操作 提前入门学习人工智能。本课程最后提供课程福利，人工智能的典型案例“聊天机器人”的初步实现。  Python实例演示 游戏 Turtle画布和游戏 Turtle是初入python的一个很好好玩的库，并且十分适合用来教导孩子如何编程，基于TK，所以运行该库时保证python已内置tk。
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
PyGame游戏引擎 包含图像、声音。建立在SDL基础上，允许实时电子游戏研发而无需被低级语言（如机器语言和汇编语言）束缚。基于这样一个设想，所有需要的游戏功能和理念都（主要是图像方面）都完全简化为游戏逻辑本身，所有的资源结构都可以由高级语言提供，如Python。
星球大战  
 
愤怒的小鸟  
 
吃豆人  
网页 网页是构成网站的基本元素，是承载各种网站应用的平台。通俗地说，您的网站就是由网页组成的，如果您只有域名和虚拟主机而没有制作任何网页的话，您的客户仍旧无法访问您的网站。
网页是一个包含HTML标签的纯文本文件，它可以存放在世界某个角落的某一台计算机中，是万维网中的一“页”，是超文本标记语言格式（标准通用标记语言的一个应用，文件扩展名为.html或.htm）。网页通常用图像档来提供图画。网页要通过网页浏览器来阅读。
 
 
数据分析 数据分析是指用适当的统计分析方法对收集来的大量数据进行分析，提取有用信息和形成结论而对数据加以详细研究和概括总结的过程。这一过程也是质量管理体系的支持过程。在实用中，数据分析可帮助人们作出判断，以便采取适当行动。
数据分析的数学基础在20世纪早期就已确立，但直到计算机的出现才使得实际操作成为可能，并使得数据分析得以推广。数据分析是数学与计算机科学相结合的产物。
 
人工智能 人工智能（Artificial Intelligence），英文缩写为AI。它是研究、开发用于模拟、延伸和扩展人的智能的理论、方法、技术及应用系统的一门新的技术科学。
人工智能是计算机科学的一个分支，它企图了解智能的实质，并生产出一种新的能以人类智能相似的方式做出反应的智能机器，该领域的研究包括机器人、语言识别、图像识别、自然语言处理和专家系统等。人工智能从诞生以来，理论和技术日益成熟，应用领域也不断扩大，可以设想，未来人工智能带来的科技产品，将会是人类智慧的“容器”。人工智能可以对人的意识、思维的信息过程的模拟。人工智能不是人的智能，但能像人那样思考、也可能超过人的智能。</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>